Fried, John H. E.; Papers ger014
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Writings of John H. E. Fried, 1931-1990; 10
  - Manuscripts, 1929-1986; 10.9; 138 file folders
    - "SS-Colonel Walter Rauff", 1975 January; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 20)
    - "Stereotypes in International Affairs", Undated; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 21)
    - "The Struggle for the Meaning of Fundamental Rights", 1943; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 22)
      Book outline.
    - "Summary of Remarks on the Representation of Kampuchea...", 1980 September 15; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 23)
    - "Symbols of Political Community. Comments by John H.E. Fried on the paper by Karl W. Deutsch", 1954; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 24)
    - "Techniques and Devices of Fascism in Italy and Germany after World War I", 1949 July 31; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 25)
    - "There Will Be No Third War", Undated; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 26)
    - 30th Anniversary of Nuremberg Trials, 1976; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 27)
    - "The True Topic of the Nuremberg Trials was the Future of Mankind", 1986 September 27; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 28)
    - "Twenty Years after Nuremberg", 1966 September; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 29)
    - UNITAR Study: "Wider Acceptance of Treaties". Early versions, 1968 December; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 30)
    - "For Wider Acceptance of United Nations Treaties", 1969; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 31)
    - UNITAR Study. Chap. 2: "Analysis of Statistical Data Regarding Acceptance of United Nations Treaties", 1969 April 10; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 32)
    - UNITAR Study. Chap. 3: "International Measures to Foster Acceptances", 1969 March; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 33)
    - UNITAR Study. Chap. 4: "Constitutional Requirements and Legislative Procedures Concerning the Conclusion of Treaties", 1969 April 07; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 34)
    - UNITAR Study. Chap. 5: "National Administrative Machinery", 1969 March 31; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 35)
    - UNITAR Study. Chap. [6]: "Final Clauses Related to Acceptance", 1969 February 04; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 36)
    - UNITAR Study. Chap. 9: "Succession or Accession to Multilateral Treaties previously extended to the dependent territories", Undated; Mimeographed typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 37)
    - UNITAR Study: "Wider Acceptance of Multilateral Treaties", 1969; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 38)
    - UNITAR Study. Unused materials, notes, Undated (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 39)
    - United Nations Security Council Book project, ca. 1971; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 40-42)
    - "U.S. Commitment to Contribute to Healing the Wounds of War and to Postwar Reconstruction of Vietnam", 1977 October 04; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 43)
    - "United States' Responsibility as Occupying Power in Indochina", 1972 October; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 44)
    - "The Universal Declaration of Human Rights: A[n] International Effort at a Synthesis of Freedom and Authority", Undated; mimeographed typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 45)
    - "Das Verbrechen am Juedischen Volk", Undated; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 46)
    - "Verbrechen gegen die Menschlichkeit der chilesischen Junta im Lichte der Nürnberger Prozesse", 1976 November 25; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 47)
    - "Visually Structured Books", ca. 1959; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 48)
    - "War by Ecoside. Some Legal Observations", Undated; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 49)
    - "What Does the Geneva Convention Say About the Release of Prisoners of War?", 1968 August 20; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 50)
    - "What Is Sovereignty?", 1956; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 51)
    - "What Was Said About Atomic Warfare in the Nuremberg Trials", 1988 November 16; Typescript (Box 23 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 52)
  - Notes on various topics, 10.10; 50 file folders
    - Anti-communism, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 1)
    - Cambodia, bombings, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 2)
    - Carter Doctrine, 1980 January (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 3)
    - Causes of War, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 4)
    - "Centrality of International Law". Brighton Conference, 1988 (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 5)
    - Democracy and Foreign Relations, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 6)
    - Fascism, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 7)
    - Functional regionalism, militarism, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 8)
    - Fundamental Human Rights, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 9-10)
    - Fundamental Human Rights - bibliography, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 11)
    - Fundamental Human Rights - Labor Problems, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 12)
    - Fundamental Human Rights vs. Nazism, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 13)
    - German Foreign Policy, 1918-1945 (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 14-15)
    - Human Rights Abuses, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 16)
    - International Law, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 17)
    - Iran hostage situation, 1979-1980 (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 18)
    - (Hitler coming to power in Germany), 1933 January 30 (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 19)
    - König article, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 20)
    - Labor and international organizations, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 21)
    - League of Nations, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 22)
    - Memoirs, Biographies, Autobiographies. Notes on books by Fried, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 23-24)
    - Militarism, Undated (Box 24 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 25)
    - Militarism and Education for War, ca. 1955 (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 1)
    - No First Use of Nuclear Weapons, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 2)
    - Nuclear War - drafts, notes for speeches, 1981-1983 (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 3)
    - Nuclear Weapons and War, including material for Salmon article, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 4-5)
    - Political parties, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 6)
    - Review of Streim/Streit books, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 7)
    - Seminar paper (Prof. MacMahon, Columbia), Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 8)
    - Somerville article, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 9)
    - Switzerland Without an Army, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 10)
    - Terrorism and the League of Nations, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 11)
    - There Will be No Third World War. Book outline, notes, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 12)
    - U.N. Spirit, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 13)
    - U.S. Military Build-up in Vietnam, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 14)
    - U.S. Foreign Relations, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 15)
    - Veto Power in the U.N., Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 16)
    - Vietnam & Southeast Asia, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 17)
    - Vietnam War, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 18)
    - Visualizing War, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 19)
    - The Waning of the Territorial State, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 20)
    - War Crimes, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 21)
    - War Powers Act, Presidential powers, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 22-23)
    - Westmoreland, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous notes, Undated (Box 25 (10-Writings of John H. E. Fried), Folder 25)
- Reprints and typescripts by other authors, 11; 154 file folders
  This series contains typescripts, reprints and clippings of articles by other authors, which in most cases were sent to Fried by the author. Many of the items are autographed and commented by the author.
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Unidentified typescript on Machiavelli, pp. 1-4 missing, Undated (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 1)
  - Ago, Roberto. "Report on the Final Stage of the Codification of International Law", 1968 July 12; Mimeographed typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 2)
  - Allen, Charles R., Undated; Typescripts, publications (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 3)
  - Almond, Harry H. Jr. "The Legality of Nuclear and Mass Destruction Weapons. The Policy Elements", 1983 June; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 4)
  - Ando, Nisuko, Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 5)
  - Arkin, William M. "Contingency Overseas Deployment of Nuclear Weapons. A Report", 1985 February; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 6)
  - Baldwin, Frank and Diane & Michael Jones. "America's Rented Troops: South Koreans in Vietnam", Undated (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 7)
  - Ball, George W. "United States Military Academy, West Point, New York. Comments", 1983 June 03; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 8)
  - Basar, Demet. "Accountability of Nuclear Scientists under International Law", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 9)
  - Bastid, Suzanne. "L'Evolution du droit international public au cours des 25 dernieres années", 1977; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 10)
  - Baudot, Marcel. "La Repression de la collaboration et l'epuration politique, administrative et economique", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 11)
  - Bedau, Hugo Adam, Undated; Reprints (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 12)
  - Beres, Louis René. "Misunderstanding Star Wars", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 13)
  - Berman, Shelley. "Primer on the Arms Race", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 14)
  - Blix, Hans. "Should dubious weapons be developed?", 1978 April; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 15)
  - Bodensieck, Heinrich, Undated; Reprints, publications (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 16)
  - Bodensieck, Heinrich. "Vietnam und der 'Neue Realismus'", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 17)
  - Borgese, G.A., Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 18)
  - Brand, G., Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 19)
  - Bryson, Lyman. "Circles of Prestige", 1954; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 20)
  - Burns, Robin, Undated; Reprints (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 21)
  - Carlson, Joel / Bert B. Lockwood, Jr. "Proposal for the Study and Organizing of Professional Committees for the Transnational Enforcement of Human Rights", 1974 April 19; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 22)
  - Chamberlain, John. "A Special Study of Kenyatta's Kenya", 1968 April; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 23)
  - Childers, Barry. "But What About Our Fear of the Russians?", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 24)
  - Clark, Roger S., Undated; Reprints, publications (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 25)
  - Clark, Roger S., 1983 March 29; 1983 May 20; Typescripts (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 26)
    "Palau Plebiscite - Failure of Proposition One (B) to obtain a 75% majority"
    "Petition Concerning the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands Presented to the United Nations Trusteeship Council on behalf of The International League for Human Rights"
  - Clarke, Arthur C. "War and Peace in the Space Age", 1982 December; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 27)
  - Contini, Paolo, Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 28)
  - Corradini, Alessandro, Undated; Reprints, publications (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 29)
  - Corradini, Alessandro, Undated; Typescripts (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 30)
    "Military Research and Development, 1982"
    "National Security Strategies and Policies and The Message of the 1978 and 1982 United Nations Special Sessions on Disarmament"
  - Cox, Arthur M., Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 31)
  - Däubler, Wolfgang. Survey on BRD views on stationing of Nukes, etc., 1984; Typescript, clipping (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 32)
  - D'Agostino, Brian. "Maintenance and Violation of Linguistic Taboos in the Politics of Disarmament and Development: A Case Study", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 33)
  - Delessert, Christiane Shields. "Should Weapons of Dubious Legality be Developed?", 1978 April 27; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 34)
  - De Smaele, A. "A Billion People in Search of Guarantees of Peace", 1984 March; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 35)
  - Deutsch, Karl W. "Symbols of Political Community", 1954; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 36)
  - Deutsch, Karl W., Undated; Reprints (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 37)
  - Deutsch, Morton. "Conflict and Its Resolution", 1965 September 05; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 38)
  - Deutsch, Morton, Undated; Reprints (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 39)
  - Douglass, Jim & Shelley. Publications, Undated (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 40)
  - Eide, Asbjørn, Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 41)
  - Epstein, William. Publications, Undated (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 42)
  - Erikson, Erik H. "Comments on Hitler's Speech of September 30, 1942", Undated; Mimeographed typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 43)
  - Feinrider, Martin. "The Strategic Defense Initiative in Light of International Law", 1985 April 26; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 44)
  - Ferencz, Benjamin, Undated; Reprints, clippings (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 45)
  - Fetscher, Iring, Undated; Reprints (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 46)
  - Fetscher, Iring. "The positive message of 'Nuremberg' for the nuclear age", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 47)
  - Fisher, Louis. "Stable Full Employment", 1962; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 48)
  - Fisher, Louis, Undated; Reprints, clippings (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 49)
  - Fries, Horace S., Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 50)
  - Gass, William H., Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 51)
  - "German Concentration and Prison Camps as Found by American and British Armies, April 1945", Undated; Mimeographed typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 52)
  - Ginzberg, Eli, Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 53)
  - Glassner, Martin Ira. "Land-Locked States and the New Law of the Sea", 1983 October; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 54)
  - Gold, Eva. "The New Face of War in El Salvador", 1986 February; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 55)
  - Goldmann, Nahum, Undated; Reprint, clipping (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 56)
  - Goldthwait, John T. "Afterword: Directions toward Morality among Nations", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 57)
  - Gottlied, M. "Stingy Finance and Laissez-Faire", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 58)
  - Graber, Sebastian, Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 59)
  - Graefrath, Bernhard, Undated; Reprints (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 60)
  - Graves, Raymond J. "The Effects of Nuclear War and the Myth of Survivability", 1982 May; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 61)
  - Greenwald, Harold, Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 62)
  - Gross, Leo, Undated; Reprints (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 63)
  - Grossman, Jerome. "A European View of 'No First Use'", 1982 October 06; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 64)
  - Heimann, Eduard, Undated; Reprints (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 65)
  - Herz, John, Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 66)
  - Hollán, S.R. "Medical Consequences of Nuclear War", Undated; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 67)
  - Jacobs, Walter Darnell, Undated; Reprint (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 68)
  - Kahler, Erich [von]. "Why Socialism? Which Socialism?", 1959 November 13; Typescript (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 69)
  - Kahler, Erich [von], Undated; Reprints (Box 26 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 70)
  - Kennan, George F. Publications, Undated (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 1)
  - Kinnard, Douglas. "Civil - Military Relations: The President and The General", 1982 April; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 2)
  - Klimentov, V.P. "Specific Features of Formation of Armed Forces in the Liberated Countries of Asia and Africa", 1982; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 3)
  - Kolko, Gabriel. "The Dynamics of Reconstruction and Victory: The PRG of South Vietnam", Undated (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 4)
    Photocopy of typescript.
  - Koppe, Karlheinz. "Äussere Sicherheit, Rüstungspolitik und Frieden als Aufgabe der Solidarität", 1981 October; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 5)
  - Kuris, Pranas. "La formation de la pensée nouvelle politico-juridique à l'époque nucléaire", 1986; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 6)
  - Lens, Sidney. Publications, Undated (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 7)
  - Liff, Zanvel A. "Impasse: Interpersonal, Intergroup and International". Photocopy of typescript, 1970; "Cooperation between Psychology and the Special Sciences for the Clarification and Solution of International Problems", Undated; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 8)
  - Liff, Zanvel A. "The United Nations as a Psycho-Political Group Process", 1970; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 9)
  - Linebarger, Paul M. A., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 10)
  - Löe, Håkon. "The Nordic Countries and the Question of Nuclear Disarmament: The Nuclear Free Zone Movements", 1982 August; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 11)
  - Logue, John J., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 12)
  - Luban, David. "The Legacies of Nuremberg", 1987; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 13)
  - MacBride, Sean, Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 14)
  - MacBride, Sean. "Human Rights in Armed Conflicts. The Inter-Relationship between the Humanitarian Laws and the Law of Human Rights", 1970; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 15)
  - MacClure, Wallace. "Viet-Nam in Perspective", ca. 1968; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 16)
  - Matheson, Michael John. "Should Weapons of Dubious Legality be Developed?", Undated; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 17)
  - McCleary, Paul F., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 18)
  - McWilliams, Wilson Carey. "Mylai and Vietnam: Moral Responsibility and Military Honor", 1971; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 19)
  - Mead, Margaret, Undated; clippings, reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 20)
  - Mecklenburg, Frank. "The Right to Peace: John Fried's Work in the Aftermath of the Nuremberg Trials", 1995; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 21)
  - Meerloo, Joost A. "Human Violence versus Animal Aggression", 1967; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 22)
  - Meerloo, Joost A., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 23)
  - Merritt, Richard L., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 24)
  - Métall, Rudolf Aladár, Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 25)
  - Mueller, Gerhard O. W., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 26)
  - Muller, Robert, Undated; Reprints (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 27)
  - Neisser, Hans, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 28)
  - Nordmann, Joë. Eulogy for Jean Bernard Herzog, Undated (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 29)
  - Nordmann, Joë, Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 30)
  - O'Brien, William V. "The Nature of the Law of War", 1980 March 21; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 31)
  - O'Brien, William V., Undated; Reprint (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 32)
  - Oeser, Edith. "Die Grundprinzipien des Völkerrechts-Element der Rechtssicherheit in den internationalen Beziehnungen", 1986 December; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 33)
  - Paech, Norman. "Frieden und Krieg", 1988; Typescript (Box 27 (11-Reprints and typescripts by other ), Folder 34)